harveynorman.ie 2018-11-17

# Cookies and Privacy Policy | Ireland

This Privacy and Cookies Policy explains how we manage your personal information that we collect about you. Please read this Privacy and Cookies Policy before using our website www.harveynorman.ie (our "website") or submitting any personal information. By using our website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy and Cookies Policy. 

### About Our Privacy And Cookies Policy

This Privacy and Cookies Policy applies to Harvey Norman Trading (Ireland) Limited (“us”, “our”, “we”, “Harvey Norman”). We are a limited liability company registered in Ireland under company number 362610 and have our registered office at Brent House, Swords Business Park, Swords, Co. Dublin, K67 Y2V0. 

We are the data controller of the personal information we hold about you. As a data controller, we respect your privacy and are committed to handling your personal information in accordance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (“GDPR”) and all other applicable legislation and regulations. 

This Privacy and Cookies Policy explains how we manage your personal information that we collect about you. Please read this Privacy and Cookies Policy before using our website www.harveynorman.ie (our "website") or submitting any personal information. By using our website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy and Cookies Policy. 

You are encouraged to review our Privacy and Cookies Policy whenever you visit our website to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used. 

If you want to contact us about any matter relating to privacy or to exercise any of your rights, please see the section [“Contact us about Privacy”](https://www.harveynorman.ie/#contact-us-about-privacy) below. 

### Collection of Your Personal Information

Your personal information is not collected if you only browse our website. 

We and/or our third party service providers may collect your personal information: 

**(a)  ** directly from you. 

**(b)  ** when you purchase a product or service from us. 

**(c)  ** when you register as a member of our website. 

**(d)  ** when you place an Order via our website. 

**(e)  ** when you enter a competition promoted by us. 

**(f)  ** where you seek employment with us. 

**(g)  ** where you access and interact with our website or the [Customer Services Team](https://www.harveynorman.ie/customer-services/contact-us.html). 

**(h)  ** when you ask us to email you information on product or service.

**(i)  **when you comment on or review our products and services.

**(j)  ** when you fill in any forms such as an incident or accident form in store.

**(k)  **when you have given a third party permission to share with us information they hold on you.

**(l)  **when we arrange the service or repair of a product on your behalf.

**(m)  **where we have CCTV systems in operation for the security and safety of our customers and employees.

**(n)  **from other sources.

The information collected may include your name, mailing or residential address, telephone number, email address and other transaction and registration details. 

If you choose not to provide us with your personal information, we may not be able to provide the information, goods or the service you may require, or to fulfil one or more other purposes of collection of your personal information. 

We do not collect your credit card or banking details as online payments are handled by Mastercard Europe SA and PayPal. Please check the [www.mastercard.us](http://www.mastercard.us/) and [www.paypal.com/ie](https://www.paypal.com/ie/webapps/mpp/home) websites for details of their privacy policies and security measures. 

### Your Rights Relating to your Personal Information 

You have certain rights in relation to the Personal Information we hold about you. Details of these rights and how to exercise them are set out below. We will require evidence of your identity before we are able to act on your request. 

**(a)  Right of Access: ** You have the right at any time to ask us for a copy of the personal information about you that we hold, and to confirm the nature of the personal information and how it is used. Where we have good reason, and if the GDPR permits, we can refuse your request for a copy of your personal information, or certain elements of the request. If we refuse your request or any element of it, we will provide you with our reasons for doing so. 

**(b)   Right of Correction:** If personal information we hold about you is not accurate, or is out of date or incomplete, and requires amendment or correction you have a right to have the data rectified, updated or completed. You can let us know by contacting us at the address or email address set out in the [“Contact us about Privacy”](https://www.harveynorman.ie/#contact-us-about-privacy) section below. 

**(c)   Right of Erasure.** In certain circumstances, you have the right to request that personal information we hold about you is erased e.g. if the personal information is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or processed or our processing of the personal information is based on your consent and there are no other legal grounds on which we may process the personal information. 

**(d)   Right to Object:** to or Restrict Processing: In certain circumstances, you have the right to object to our processing of your personal information by contacting us at the address or email address set out in the [“Contact us about Privacy”](https://www.harveynorman.ie/#contact-us-about-privacy) section below. For example, if we are processing your personal information on the basis of our legitimate interests and there are no compelling legitimate grounds for our processing which override your rights and interests. You also have the right to object to use of your personal information for direct marketing purposes. You may also have the right to restrict our use of your personal information, such as in circumstances where you have challenged the accuracy of the information and during the period where we are verifying its accuracy. 

**(e)   Right of Data Portability.** In certain instances, you have a right to receive any personal information that we hold about you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. You can ask us to transmit that Information to you or directly to a third party organisation. 

This right exists in respect of personal information that: 

  * You have provided to us previously; and 
  * Is processed by us using automated means. 

While we are happy for such requests to be made, we are not able to guarantee technical compatibility with a third party organisation’s systems. 

You can exercise any of the above rights by contacting us at the address or e-mail address set out in the [“Contact us about Privacy”](https://www.harveynorman.ie/#contact-us-about-privacy) section below. You can exercise your rights free of charge. 

Most of the above rights are subject to limitations and exceptions. We will provide reasons if we are unable to comply with any request for the exercise of your rights. 

### Our Use of Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of text that is placed within the memory of a computer and can be later retrieved by web page servers. We use cookies to enhance your interaction and convenience with our website and do not use cookies to record any personal information. 

Cookies may record information about your visit, including the type of browser and operating system you use, the previous site you visited, your server’s IP address, the pages you access and the information downloaded by you. While this anonymous statistical data may be aggregated and used in broader statistical analysis by us and our web monitoring service provider to improve our services, at no time can we personally identify you as the source of that data. 

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue you with a cookie when you log on to our website and you are deemed to have consented to the use of the cookie. The purpose for which the cookie is used is for identification of a specific user during a session on our website e.g. when a user is logged on to the website to identify what permissions they have and what items are in their shopping cart. The cookie will be deleted at the end of the website session. 

### Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

We may disclose your personal information to any of our related entities, which includes our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries. 

You acknowledge and consent that by providing your personal information to us that we may use and disclose your personal information for the following purposes: 

**(a)  ** to facilitate and process your Order. 

**(b)  ** to carry out or respond to your requests. 

**(c)  ** to our third party service providers to assist us in providing and improving our services to you, and to analyse trends in sales and better understand our customers’ needs or to develop, improve and market our goods and services to you.

**(d)  ** for regulatory reporting and compliance with our legal obligations.

**(e)  **to regulatory bodies and law enforcement officials and agencies to protect against fraud and for related security purposes.

**(f)  ** where you have provided your consent, to include in a database compiled by us or our third party service provider for use by us or our third party service provider in direct marketing of promotions, product and services we think may interest you.

**(g)  ** to seek your feedback in relation to customer satisfaction and our relationship with you.

**(h)  ** to our related entities for internal accounting and administration.

**(i)  ** to monitor or improve the quality and standard of service provided to you by us.

**(j)  ** to our successors and/or assigns, including any party that may purchase all or part of our business.

**(k)  ** to better understand your preferences. 

Our third party service providers are organisations that assist us with research, mail, advertising, delivery, security, professional advisory, banking, payment processing or technology services. Where we engage third party service providers to perform services for us those third parties may be required to handle your personal information. Under these circumstances those third parties must safeguard this information and must only use it for the purposes for which it was supplied.

Other than the above, we will not disclose your personal information without your consent unless disclosure is either necessary to prevent a threat to life or health, authorised or required by law, reasonably necessary to enforce the law or necessary to investigate a suspected unlawful activity or any breach of any of the [Website Terms of Use](https://www.harveynorman.ie/corporate-information/website-terms-of-use.html) of our website or our [Online Sale Terms](https://www.harveynorman.ie/corporate-information/online-sale-terms.html). 

Any permitted handling of personal information under any exemptions under the GDPR or any other applicable legislation will take priority over this Privacy and Cookies Policy to the extent of any inconsistency. 

### Legal basis for Processing your Personal Information 

Under GDPR, the main grounds that we rely upon in order to process your personal information are the following: 

**(a)  ** Necessary for compliance with a legal obligation: we are subject to certain legal requirements which may require us to process your information. We may also be obliged by law to disclose your Information to a regulatory body or law enforcement agency.

**(b)  ** Performance of Contract: We may process your personal information where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract. 

**(c)  ** Necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests: either we, or a third party, will need to process your personal information for the purposes of our (or a third party’s) legitimate interests, provided we have established that those interests are not overridden by your rights and freedoms, including your right to have your Personal Information protected. Our legitimate interests include responding to requests and enquiries from you or a third party, fulfilling sales, optimising our website and customer experience, informing you about our products and services and ensuring that our operations are conducted in an appropriate and efficient manner.

**(d)  ** Consent: in some circumstances, we may ask for your consent to process your Personal Information in a particular way. 

### Providing Personal Information About Another Person

You represent to us that where you provide personal information to us about another person, you are authorised to provide that information to us, and that you will inform that person who we are, how we use and disclose their information, and that they can gain access to that information. You agree that you will inform that other person of this Privacy and Cookies Policy and that they may review and download a copy on our website [www.harveynorman.ie](https://www.harveynorman.ie/)

### Securing Your Personal Information

We have implemented appropriate physical, electronic and managerial security procedures in order to protect personal information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction. Access to your personal information is limited to those who specifically need it to conduct their responsibilities. 

We and our third party service providers take reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify your personal information where it is no longer required and to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, disclosure, loss, misuse and alteration. 

### Accuracy of Data 

We take reasonable steps to ensure that the information we hold about you is accurate, complete and up-to-date. To assist us in doing this, please provide us with the correct information and inform us if your details change. You may update your membership details at any time by accessing your membership account or by contacting our [Customer Services Team](https://www.harveynorman.ie/customer-services/contact-us.html). If we deny you access to your personal information, we will provide you with the reason for such denial. 

### Accuracy of Data 

We will only retain your personal information for as long as is necessary for the purpose or purposes for which we have collected it. The criteria that we use to determine retention periods will be determined by the nature of the data and the purposes for which it is kept. For example, if we receive your information through a competition entry, we will retain your data for as long as is necessary to administer the competition. In certain circumstances, once we have deleted or anonymised your data, we may need to retain parts of it (for example, your email address), in order to comply with our obligations under GDPR or other legislation, or for fraud detection purposes. 

### Linked Sites

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites. 

### Transmission of Your Data

While care is taken to protect your personal information received from you via our website, unfortunately no data transmission over the Internet is guaranteed as 100% secure. Accordingly, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you send to us or receive from us online. This is particularly true for information you send to us via email as we have no way of protecting that information until it reaches us. Once we receive your personal information, we are required to protect it in accordance with the GDPR and all other applicable legislation. 

### Where we Store Your Personal Data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"), and in particular to our hosting company, Yoogalu Pty Ltd and its related bodies corporate, which is located in Australia. It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy and Cookies Policy. 

### Changes to Our Policy

From time to time it may be necessary for us to review and revise this Privacy and Cookies Policy. We reserve the right to change our Privacy and Cookies Policy at any time. Amendments or replacements of the Privacy and Cookies Policy will be posted on our website and where we have your email address we will advise you of material changes to our Privacy Policy. Your use of our website will constitute your acceptance of any revisions, amendments or replacements to the Privacy and Cookies Policy. 

### Direct Marketing

You have the right to ask us at any time not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by not checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting our [Customer Services Team](https://www.harveynorman.ie/customer-services/contact-us.html). All emails, SMS and newsletters from this website allow you to opt-out of further mailings by clicking on the link or responding “unsubscribe”. 

### Consent 

To the extent that we are processing your personal information based on your consent you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. You can do this by unsubscribing using the link in any direct marketing communication or by contacting us at the email address set out in the [“Contact us about Privacy”](https://www.harveynorman.ie/#contact-us-about-privacy) Section below. 

### Complaints

If you are unhappy about our use of your Personal Information, you can contact us at the address or e-mail address above. You are also entitled to lodge a complaint with the Irish Data Protection Commissioner's Office using any of the below contact methods: 

Post: Office of the Data Protection Commissioner   
Canal House  
Station Road   
Portarlington   
Co. Laois   
R32 AP23 

Harvey Norman Ireland Online Privacy Policy Version 2.0
